GITHUB.COM/YOUN0038 LINKEDIN.COM/IN/AY0038

ANNA YOUNG

Software Engineer



📻 111 BREAKWATER BASTROP TX 78602 💌 ANNAYOUNG9216@GMAIL.COM

PROFILE

Two years of web development experience and 9+ years of working in and leading groups have produced excellent team building and interpersonal skills. I have a passion for people and service to others at the core of everything I do. I believe my diverse experience, curiosity, and love of problemsolving will help me create lasting value for your company.

EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE INSTRUCTOR, OK CODERS & I-CCEW

AUGUST 2020 - PRESENT

- Created and taught front-end development curriculum for 30 students from the general public and full-stack development curriculum for five software engineer interns.
- Served as a technical advisor to the development team over the course of the semester project.
- Co-led software engineer interviews for incoming interns through evaluating an applicant's technical experience.

SOFTWARE TEAM LEAD/FELLOW, RONNIE K. IRANI CENTER FOR THE CREATION OF ECONOMIC WEALTH AUGUST 2019 - DECEMBER 2020

- As a Team Lead, led a team of software engineers to deliver a prototype to improve PropertyProtect, LLC's ability to make data-driven sales decisions.
- · As a Fellow, led a team of consulting associates and software development interns to deliver a launch strategy and user dashboard for MindEd Tribe's gamified platform.
- As an intern, worked with ConsumerAffairs to create a prototype that increased customer conversion rate by 137% and account creation rate by 42% through strategic changes to the online matching tool.

TEACHING ASSISTANT ELECTRONIC'S LABRATORY, UNIVERSITY OF OKLAHOMA

- JANUARY 2020-MAY 2020
- Prepared students enrolled in an upper-level Electronics Laboratory to develop proficiency in designing, building, and troubleshooting circuits.
- Taught mathematical concepts to students for them to understand their circuit designs better.
- · Collaborated and communicated with professor and other teaching assistants to provide a quality working environment for the students.

SALES REPRESENTATIVE, CALDWELL SALES

DECEMBER 2015 - FEBRUARY 2017

- Leveraged organizational skills and initiative to provide product education and sales support for over 20 natural health brands in retail stores such as Whole Foods Market across the Oklahoma and Arkansas territory.
- · Established cooperative relationships with store buyers by listening to their department needs and recommending effective solutions for their location.

EDUCATION

SKILLS

B.S. Computer Engineering Minor: Computer Science GPA: 3.90 | Class of 2020

PROFICIENT: HTML, CSS/SASS, JAVASCRIPT, PYTHON,

FLASK, BOOTSTRAP

University of Oklahoma | Norman, OK

FAMILIAR: JAVA, REACT.JS, C++, MATLAB